Go, Eren!
In the year 850...
For the first time,
humanity recovered part of its
territory from the Titans.
Though at great cost.
Then I welcome everyone
here to the Survey Corps!
This is a true salute!
Offer up your hearts!
Yes, sir!
You have done well to endure your fear.
You are brave soldiers.
You have my heartfelt respect.
A month later,
led by Erwin Smith, the
Survey Corps left Karanes
to find a route to Zhiganshina,
where it's believed the secrets
of the Titans are held.
We will now begin the 57th
expedition beyond the walls!
Onward!
Oh, my friend!
This is a victory for us!
Our fame starts here!
Oh, my friend!
Let us celebrate this victory for the next battle!
"I died for naught"
I won't let it end like that for you
until I am the last one standing
The enemy is cruel... We will kill...
The enemy is colossal... We will jump...
In our hands we hold blades of glory
and sing in the name of victory
We bear the wings of freedom on our backs
Swearing iron determination upon our hearts,
we slash apart the circle of idiocy
and soar through the sky
with our wings of freedom
Female Titan: The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 1
Ahead, to the left, a 10-meter class!
I am very interested in seeing
what's inside its stomach...
But I'll leave it to the support team!
Damn!
Not deep enough.
Defend the formation!
Stay strong!
Leave it to the support
team, and keep going!
Onward! Onward!
The support teams will only
accompany us to the old city area.
Once we're past that,
it's completely Titan territory.
The long-range scouting formation devised
by Commander Erwin is our only hope.
We, the special ops squad, are here.
Sir, can they...
Can my classmates beat the Titans?
Huh?
What have you been doing the past month?
Listen, brat...
The most crucial part
of an expedition is in how
you avoid fighting Titans
Go into long-range scouting formation!
See ya, Armin.
If you run into a Titan,
don't piss your pants!
Right!
Same to you, Jean.
Row 3-3: Relay
The vanguard is to spread
out in a semi-circle.
But stay within visual
range of one another.
Row 5-Center: Standby
Position yourselves at fixed intervals.
Extend the recon and message relay
range as far as possible.
We'll be fine...
Calm down!
It's primarily the forward recon squad
that will encounter Titans.
As soon as one is sighted,
they'll fire a red smoke round.
Anyone who sees the flare should fire
the same round to relay the signal.
When the Commander sees it,
he'll fire a green smoke round,
and show the formation where to go.
Thus, the entire formation can advance
toward the goal, while avoiding Titans.
But sometimes, due to terrain or obstacles,
a Titan won't be sighted until
it's within the formation.
Red... Red...
Red smoke round...
Blause! Over here!
Damn it! Did we let one through?
We'll draw it this way.
Blause, get over here!
I'll handle it!
Split off!
Yes, sir!
Sir...
Back into position!
He ran out of gas.
Something's wrong...
It's been a while since we
saw the red smoke round,
but they still haven't reformed.
It can't be...
Note that this strategy only
works on normal Titans,
whose behavior can be easily predicted.
A black smoke round?
Is a Titan ignoring the nearby humans
and heading for the formation's center?
It has to be...
That's
an Aberrant!
It's only necessary to fight Aberrants,
whose behavior is unpredictable.
Damn, we'll have to fight it...
Sys, go for the neck!
I'll stop it!
Roger!
Using Maneuver Gear on flat
terrain is a huge disadvantage.
It almost never works.
But I can't let it disrupt the formation.
I think that's Arlert over there.
I don't want one of the
new guys to run into it.
We kill it here!
Now, Sys!
You did it, Squad Leader Ness!
Did I get him?
You came for me?
That's my partner...
I love you, Shallot!
Again?
What is the right flank recon squad doing?
If it ignored them and came this way,
it must be another Aberrant.
Oh, fine...
Sys, we do it again.
Right.
But we've got the worst luck,
doing this twice in a row...
And I think it's at least
a fourteen-meter class.
This one will be tough.
What's that?
It's too fast!
Don't let it reach Arlert!
Sys!
Right!
No... No.
That's no Aberrant.
It's intelligent!
Like the Armored or
Colossal Titans, or Eren...
A human in the body of a Titan!
B-But who?
Why?
This is bad! What should I do?
I'm going to die, too...
I'll be killed!
Go! Run!
What does it...
No, what do they...
What do they want?
Someone tell them...
That the right flank recon squad
has been wiped out...
A Female Titan brought
a huge Titan army!
Is anyone there?
It's not going to kill me?
Why?
It removed my hood...
To... To look at my face?
Armin!
Reiner!
Hey, can you stand?
You won't last outside the walls
unless you're on horseback...
Hurry!
Right!
I saw the smoke round
signaling an Aberrant.
Was it that one there with the nice ass?
That's no Aberrant...
It's a human in a Titan body!
What was that?
Wait a second.
We need to fire a smoke round first.
H-Hurry...
There's an emergency over there.
With a smoke round, I'll...
Wait... I think Jean fired it.
It came from the right flank.
Does that mean we're so compromised,
we can't continue the mission?
Looks like the right flank recon
squad was partially wiped out...
Titans, tons of them.
I don't know why,
but there are lots of fast ones.
For now, we're holding them back,
but recon is no longer possible...
We've taken heavy losses,
and if we aren't careful,
we'll be destroyed!
That Titan came from the same direction.
No way...
Was it leading the Titans?
It?
Why is a Titan over there?
An Aberrant?
No, it's a human in a Titan body...
Someone with the same ability as Eren.
What?
Why do you think that, Armin?
The Titans only eat us.
We're just killed in the process.
Killing us isn't ever
specifically their goal.
But when Sys aimed for its weak spot,
it crushed him and smashed
him into the ground.
It killed him to kill,
rather than to eat him.
Its nature is different from the others.
When the Colossal and Armored
Titans destroyed the walls,
it must've been the one that
brought that army of Titans.
Their goal has consistently
been to attack all humanity!
No, maybe not.
It felt like it was looking for someone...
If that is the case,
could it be looking for...
Could it be looking for Eren?
Eren?
Eren's with Squad Levi, which is
in charge of the right flank.
The right flank?
The plans I got had them
to the rear of the left flank.
Mine said they were near
the front of the right...
Wait, there's no way they'd
be on the front lines.
So where are they?
Probably the safest place in the formation.
Which means in the center,
and toward the rear...
Armin!
There's no time to think.
Smoke rounds can't possibly indicate
how much of a threat it poses!
At this rate, it'll wipe out command.
Then the formation will fall apart,
and that'll be the end.
What are you trying to say?
In other words,
at this range, we may still be
able to draw its attention.
We may be able to buy time to withdraw.
Maybe... Maybe...
But it really is intelligent.
To it, we are nothing but
insignificant insects.
It'll just crush us...
Seriously?
That's scary...
Hey, are you really Jean?
The Jean I know never thinks
of anyone but himself.
Don't be an ass...
I just don't want those charred bones I saw
to be disappointed in me!
I...
I know what I have to do now!
And this is the job we chose.
Help me!
Put on your hood.
As far forward as you can...
So that your face is hidden from it.
I don't think it will kill us until
it knows who we are!
Oh...
You believe if it thinks we might
be Eren, it won't kill us?
If nothing else, it'll make me feel better.
Let's just hope it has poor eyesight!
Armin, I thought it was creepy
how you always clung to Eren.
But I've always thought you had it in you.
Uh, thanks.
But "creepy"? That's really mean...
It's going much more slowly
than when I first saw it.
Is it tired?
If it runs at that speed
again, we'll be too late!
Now's our chance... We have to do it now!
Listen up... Remember what I said.
Try to draw its attention
for as long as possible,
to give the formation time to withdraw!
Keep it here as long as you can.
If we could cut its Achilles tendon,
that'd be more than enough.
But don't do anything stupid...
Don't try to kill it!
It's aware of the weak spot on its neck.
It's totally different than other Titans...
It is impossible to kill.
At least, not by any normal human being.
However...
If it's those two... Maybe...
Armin!
This one...
Its movements are much more
precise than the others' are!
Damn it.
I...
I underestimated it!
It protected its neck...
Jean!
Damn it! I can't get away!
I'm going to die!
Once it grasps my wire, it's over!
Jean!
Avenge the bastard who rushed to his death!
Armin?
It stopped?
That's the one...
That's the one that killed him!
He rushed to his death on the right flank!
Avenge him!
What happened?
Did Armin hit his head and go insane?
This isn't the time...
R-Reiner?
It crushed my best friend!
I saw his body under its foot!
He's going straight for the neck?
No, it's working!
While it's distracted by Armin!
H-Hey...
H-Hey... Reiner, you...
Reiner did it!
Mikasa was so strong, I forgot.
But he's really strong and reliable, too...
We've bought enough time, right?
Let's get the hell away from it!
If it isn't a man-eater,
it won't follow us!
Look...
That big bitch got scared
and decided to go home!
No... Why?
That's toward the center rear.
Is it
heading toward Eren?
If we suppose that I am not me,
Can you say with certainty that you are you?
Will you be able to pick up after yourself
Once your sand-like shell breaks and your heart crumbles?
I could hear someone calling
But now my ears are just ringing
It's as if time has frozen
Now, wake up
I began to walk through a deep dark abyss
As swift as a gale, I escaped for my life
I felt like a living corpse
We break out of our walls
To reunite in worlds we've yet to map
"You damn monster!"
Not even the highly experienced Survey Corps soldiers can stop the female Titan.
And so, the monster finally spots Eren in a forest of giant trees.
Forest of Giant Trees: The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 2